

Salvador Olvera Nava

Jr. Full Stack Developer

@ salvador.olvera@outlook.com

salvador-olvera-n

Salvador-ON

salvador-on.github.io

CAREER SUMMARY

Full-Stack Remote Software Developer with a passion for coding and creating web applications with intuitive UX, UI effects, and responsive design. I have been extensively involved in developing web applications such as front-end user interface, and backend database management. I have experience working with remote teams, and advanced proficiencies in HTML, CSS, SASS, JavaScript, Ruby, Ruby on Rail, and React/Redux. With 5 years of experience in the tech field as a Mechatronic Engineer.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Jr Full-Stack Developer.

Microverse Web Development Program - Remote.

2020

Worked remotely doing pair programming with colleagues from other parts of the world, increasing the code quality of the developed projects.

Built over 30 Front-end and Back-end projects during the program. Using different technologies and going out of my comfort zone.

Made unit and integration tests on projects, to keep bugs out of production, helping to improve the quality of the projects.

Mentored new developers, helping and guiding them in the coding development. Reviewed and tested their codes and giving feedback to improve it, and helping them to understand some concepts.

Technologies used:

Ruby on Rails

React/Redux

JavaScript

Webpack

HTML5/CSS3/SASS

Adobe CS

Chief Operating Officer.

Tridi Mx.

2016 - 2019

Supervised and lead the daily operations of the company including manufacturing operations, engineering, purchase, human resources, and administration.

Developed the annual strategic plan to improve the key performance indicators, improving production efficiency by 15%.

Managed the logistics entry of the company to the Stratasys Global Manufacturing Network. From the development of the start plan of the new production lines to the startup, and lead the daily manufacturing operations.

Ensured proper management of resources, distribution of goods and services to customers, and supply chain.

Technologies used:

Ganttic

(Python)

Google Spreadsheets

Zapier

JotForm

Asana

Adobe CS

Adittive Manufacture Chief Officer.

Tridi Mx.

2015 - 2016

Developed and implemented a quality validation system for the manufactured items, helping to avoid sending defective items.

Developed and implemented a Manufacturing Execution System, helping the company to track and capture data, of the processes and outcomes of the manufacturing process.

Planned and executed daily production schedules, supervised, coordinated, and evaluated Human Resources to ensure daily production.

Standardized the manufacturing operations processes including cad file preparations, manufacturing, post-treatments, maintenance, and shipments.

Technologies used:

Embedded Systems Solidworks / Inventor

Google Spreadsheets

Jr Engineer.

Tridi Mx.

2014 - 2015

Researched and developed the post-treatments. Helping to improve the quality of the pieces.

Developed and implemented tools and jigs, with the aim of reducing scrap and ensuring product quality and increasing the safety of the processes.

Researched and developed the improvement of the software parameters and hardware on the additive manufacturing equipment. Improving the visual quality of the pieces, reducing scrap by 10%, and post-treatment times by 15%.

Technologies used:

Arduino

Raspberry Pi

Python)

Google Spreadsheets

Solidworks / Inventor

SKILLS & TOOLS

Frontend

HTML/CSS/SASS

Bootstrap

JavaScript

React/Redux

Adobe CS (Ai, Ps, Pr)

Backend

Ruby/Rails

SQL

Skills

Project Management

Lean Manufacturing **Continual Improvement Process**

Problem Solving Code Review Git Linux Heroku Netlify **Unit Testing** Wireframing

Teamwork Mockups Creativity Proactivity **Pair Programming**

EDUCATION

Full-Stack Developer.

Microverse Web Development Program. 2020

Mechatronic Engineering. Universidad del Valle de México.

2011 - 2015

Manager Mentor.

Harvard Business School. 2012

Continuous Process Automatization.

Festo.

2012

Solidworks CSWA. Solidworks.

2012

AWARDS

Taureate Award for **Excellence in Robotic Engineering**

Team leader of Mexico team and finalist at the Laureate Award for Excellence in Robotics Engineering, Second edition, 2015.

LANGUAGE

Spanish (Native)

English (Professional)